Finding Aid for the Ernst Toch Papers PASC-M.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Photographic Material, Series 1.; 5 boxes
  - Photos in the press, Subseries 15.
    - "Some Composers Who Have Gone Hollywood" from Musical America, February 10, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Photos of Toch and various other composers. Original and xerox copy.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Toch in the "San Francisco News", March 11, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Article in "Der Tag", 1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Toch and Kurt Weill in "Frankfurter Zeitung", 1927 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      original and photocopy
    - photo from "Die Wochenschau", Oct. 17, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - press photo from "Die Musik" (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Toch and Charles Munch rehearsing "Princess" (Box 2, Folder 17)
      unknown article
    - sketches of Toch and Hindemith in NY Times, Aug. 10, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      From article by Alfred Einstein.
    - NY Times Article "News and Comment of the Current Week in Music", July 24, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Slides, open-reel film, proofs and negatives., Subseries 16.
    - portrait of Ernst Toch by Max Band, slide (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - portrait of Ernst Toch by Max Band, slide (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - portrait of Ernst Toch by Max Band, slide (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ernst and Lilly Toch (shortly before their marriage)., 1916; slide (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Toch sitting at a patio table, slide (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - sketch of Ernst Toch, slide (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - close portrait of Toch, slide (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - portrait of Toch, slide (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Toch at the piano, slide (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Toch playing the piano, slide (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Toch posed by the piano, slide (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Toch posed at the piano, slide (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Toch at his desk, slide (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Toch at his desk; dup. of item 13, slide (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Portrait of Toch, slide (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Toch working on a score, slide (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Toch relaxing at his desk, slide (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Flyer for commemorative concert at UCLA, Nov. 22, slide (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Dedication for Irv and Franzi's wedding, slide (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - unidentified (orchestral work). (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 8mm film of unknown contents (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Film of Toch, 1932; 16mm, 4 min. (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Film of Ernst Toch in New York, guest of his cousin, John Bass, who took the pictures. Includes footage of Toch with a monkey, miming a juggler routine, and performing magic.
    - photographic proofs (Box 3, Folder 23)
      7 pages
    - photographic negatives (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Derivative images, Subseries 17.
    Digital reproductions and microfilm.
    - Digital image of Box 4, Item 84. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      1 CD.
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - Digital image of Box 1, Item 29a. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Toch photo printing plate (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 1)
      None shall escape. Columbia Pictures, 1944. Score, 216p.
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 2)
      "Von Coustanze"
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 3)
      Address unknown. Columbia Pictures, 1944. Holograph score, 171 p.
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 4)
      Der Facher, op. 51. Microfilm of original manuscript.
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 4)
      Address Unknown. Columbia Pictures, 1944. Piano-conductor score, 69 p.
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 5)
      Burlesken, op. 31, 1923. Autograph with letter to Paul Hirsch, 1925.
    - Microfilm (Box 5a, Folder 6)
      Four manuscripts: Der Facher, op. 51; Variations on "Unser dummer"; Die Prinzessin auf der Erbse, op. 43; Das Wasser, op. 53.
    - Microfilm (Box 5b, Folder 1)
      None shall escape. Columbia Pictures, 1944. Piano-conductor score, 57 p.
    - Microfilm (Box 5b, Folder 2)
      Ladies in Retirement. Columbia Pictures, 1941. Piano-conductor score, 67p.
    - Microfilm (Box 5b, Folder 3)
      Das Wasser, op. 53. Microfilm of original manuscript.
    - Microfilm (Box 5b, Folder 5)
      Variations on "Unser dummerPobel meint" (Mozart) for piano and orchestra. Original manuscript.
    - Musk zum Shauspiel "Die Heilige von U.S.A.", Negative microfilm of manuscript. (Box 5b, Folder 6)
    - Microfilm, Microfilm of score. (Box 5b, Folder 7)
      The Last Tale
    - Microfilm, Negative film print of manuscript. (Box 5b, Folder 8)
      Music fuer Turandot und Die Raeuber.
    - Microfilm, Negative microfilm. (Box 5b, Folder 9)
      Villa Majestic Guest Book
  - Uncatalogued Photographs, Subseries 18.
    - Grouped in envelopes: Miscellaneous important images, Ella Zwack's photo album, Photo album featuring Ernst and young Franzi, Lilly's side of the family, Ella Zwack, Franzi, Miscellaneous. (Box 212)
    - Grouped in evelopes: Toch alone, Lilly, Toch with miscellaneous others, Miscellaneous musicians 1900-1920, WWI, Miscellaneous others, Ernst's mother, Ernst's sister. (Box 213)
- Sound Recordings, Series 2.
  Boxes 6-13. Listed by opus number. Titles and performers listed as noted on recording container. This series consists of musical sound recordings only. For recorded interviews, see Series 11 "Interviews."
  - Open reel: Music, Subseries 1.
    Box 6, Items 1-264; Box 7, Items 1-7; Box 8, Items 1-3.
    - Burlesken, Op. 31, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Cello Concerto, Op. 35, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Cello Concerto, Op. 35, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Divertimento, Op. 37, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Komodie for Orchester, Op. 42, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Lieder, Op. 41, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Lieder, Op. 41, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, 1974; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      (La Forge)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, 1973; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Also includes Green Room Discussion 9/25/49 WCBS-FM.
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Concerto, Op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Princess and the Pea, Op. 43, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Princess and the Pea, Op. 43, 1961; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Quartet in A minor, Op. 12, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Quartet, Op. 12, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Selections, 1973; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Band 1: Piano Solos; Band 2-4: Violin - Piano Sonata Op. 21; Band 5: Toch's speech; Band 6: Toch's "Music of Today" Speech.
    - Selections, 1967; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Kammersymphonie (premiere) -- Tanz Suite, Op. 30.
    - Selections, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Pinocchio Overture (Chicago Symphony Orchestra, Stockowski, conductor) -- Three Burlesques, Op. 31 -- [unidentified selections] -- "Spitzweg" Serenade. Louis Kaufman and Grischa Monaseiwitsch, violin, Raymond Manhennik, viola (VOX LP).
    - Selections, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Piano Concerto, Op. 38 -- Symphony #5. Performers: Ernst Toch, piano, first work; Boston Symphony Orchestra, second work.
    - Spiel für Blasinstrumente, Op. 39, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Spiel für Blasinstrumente, Op. 39, 1969; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Spiel für Blasinstrumente, Op. 39, 1970; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Spiel für Blasorchester, Op. 39, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - String Quartet in C Major, Op. 26, 1973; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - String Quartet in C Major, Op. 26, 1973; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - String Quartet, Op. 26, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Three Burlesques, Op. 31, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Three Pantomimes (Burlesques?), open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Violin - Piano Sonata, "Profiler" (7 piano pieces), open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      Ernst Toch, piano, first work; Jacob Gimpel, piano, second work.
    - Violin and Piano Sonata, Op. 21, 1965; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
      General note
      Recorded in Aspen, CO.
    - Violin and Piano Sonata, Op. 21, open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Violin and Piano Sonata, Op. 21, 1965 August 7; open reel audio tape (Box 6)
    - Piano Quintet, 1951; open reel audio tape (Box 7)
      Publisher no.: 1212
    - Selections, open reel audio tape (Box 7)
      Kammersymphonie (premiere) -- Tanz Suite, Op. 30(UCLA Chamber Orchestra, Mehli Mehta, cond.) -- Symphony No. 4 (USC Orchestra, Ingolf Dahl, cond.)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, Symphony No. 1, open reel audio tape (Box 7)
      Profilen: 7 pieces for piano. Also performed by Jacob Gimpel, piano.
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano. Symphony No. 1., 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 7)
    - Symphonies 1 and 2, 1950-1952; open reel audio tape (Box 7)
    - Toch Festival Memorial Concert - UCLA., 1975 November 22; open reel audio tape (Box 7)
    - Poems to Martha, Op. 66., open reel audio tape (Box 8)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73., open reel audio tape (Box 8)
    - Selections, open reel audio tape (Box 8)
      Ladies in Retirement (uneditied) -- Spitzweg Serenade -- 3 Israeli Dances -- The Covenant -- Big Ben.
    - [Bunte?] Suite for Orchestra, open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Bunte Suite for Orchestra, Op. 48, open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Bunte Suite für Orchester, Op. 48, 1969; open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Bunte Suite, Op. 48, 1963; open reel audio tape (Box 206)
      Recorded a Royce Hall UCLA.
    - Bunte Suite, Op. 48, open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Bunte Suite, Op. 48, 1963 April 28; open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Kleinstadtbilder, Op. 49; Ideas, Op. 69, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Sonata, Op. 44, open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Violin Sonata, Op. 44, Divertimento for Violin & Viola, Op. 37b, open reel audio tape (Box 206)
    - Miniature Ouverture, Op. 51, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 46)
    - Music for Orchestra and Baritone, Op. 60, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 47)
    - Piano Concerto No. 2, Op. 61, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 48)
    - Piano Concerto No. 2, Op. 61, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 49)
    - Big Ben, Op. 62, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 50)
    - Big Ben, Op. 62, 1963; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 51)
    - Big Ben, Op. 62, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 52)
    - String Trio, Op. 63, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 53)
    - String Trio, Op. 63, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 54)
    - Piano Quintet, Op. 64, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 55)
    - Piano Quintet, Op. 64, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 56)
    - Piano Quintet, Op. 64, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 57)
    - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Op. 65, 1975; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 58)
    - Selections, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 59)
      Psalm from Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Op. 65 -- Covenant -- First Symphony.
    - W. A. Mozart's Variations on "Unser dummer Pöbel meint.."; Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Op. 65, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 60)
    - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Op. 65, 1963; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 61)
    - Introduction to Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 62)
    - Toch's Introduction to the Cantata of the Bitter Herbs., 1968; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 63)
      Read by William Mallock.
    - Pinocchio Overture; Poems to Martha, Op. 66, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 64)
    - Poems to Martha, Op. 66 cont.; Dance of Marionettes., open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 65)
    - Pinocchio Overture; Poems to Martha, Op. 66, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 66)
    - Symphony No. 1. Movements 1 and 2, 1953; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 67)
    - Symphony No. 1. Movements 3 and 4, 1953; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 68)
    - First Symphony, Op. 72 (Part 2); Serenade for Two Violins and Viola, op. 25, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 69)
    - Symphony No. 2, Op. 73, open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 70)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, 1955 February 19; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 71)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, 1952; open reel audio tape (Box 206, Folder 72)
      Performance in Boston.
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, open reel audio tape (Box 207, Folder 73)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, open reel audio tape (Box 207, Folder 74)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 75)
      Doraty, cond.
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, July 15, 1970 (Box 207, Folder 76)
      Symphonieorchester des Bayerischen Rundfunks, Rafael Kubelik, cond.
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 77)
      Boston Symphony Orchestra.
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 78)
      Boston Symphony, Charles Munch, cond.
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 79)
    - Symphony No. 2, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 80)
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73 (Box 207, Folder 81)
    - String Quartet No. 8, Op. 74, 1954 (Box 207, Folder 82)
      Premiere recording. New Music Quartet, Pasadena.
    - Various (Box 207, Folder 83)
      Symphony No. 3, Op. 75 (Capitol P-8364). Pinocchio Overture (MGM 3144). Circus Overture, (Col. CL 758). The Chinese Flute (MGM 3546).
    - Symphony No. 3, Op. 75 (Box 207, Folder 84)
    - Symphony No. 3, Op. 75 (Box 207, Folder 85)
      Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, William Steinburg, cond.
    - Symphony No. 3, Op. 75 (Box 207, Folder 86)
      Copy. Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, William Steinburg, cond.
    - Symphony No. 3, Op. 75 (Box 207, Folder 87)
    - Peter Pan, Op 76 (Box 207, Folder 88)
    - Peter Pan, Op. 76 (Box 207, Folder 89)
    - Peter Pan, Op. 76 (Box 207, Folder 90)
      Seattle Symphony, Katims, cond.
    - Peter Pan, Op. 76, 1957 (Box 207, Folder 91)
      Indianapolis Symphony Orchestra, Izler Solomon, cond.
    - Vanity of Vanities, Op. 79 (Box 207, Folder 92)
    - Vanity of Vanities, Op. 79, 1954 (Box 207, Folder 93)
    - Vanity of Vanities, Op. 79, 1954 (Box 207, Folder 94)
    - Symphony No. 4 Op. 80; Big Ben Variations (Box 207, Folder 95)
    - Symphony No. 4, Op. 80, 1962 (Box 207, Folder 96)
      USC Symphony Orchestra, Dalil cond.
    - Symphony No. 4, Nov 22, 1957 (Box 207, Folder 97)
      Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, Antal Dorati, cond.
    - Symphony No. 4, Op. 80, Oct 28, 1962 (Box 207, Folder 98)
      USC Symphony Orchestra, Joseph Dahl, cond.
    - Symphony No. 4, Op. 80 (Box 207, Folder 99)
    - Music For Winds and Percussion, Op. 83, Oct 12, 1959 (Box 207, Folder 100)
      Premeire performance.
    - Music For Winds and Percussion, Op. 83 (Box 207, Folder 101)
    - Various (Box 207, Folder 102)
      Pinocchio Overture, Five Pieces for Winds and Percussion (Philadelphia Wind Quintet), Phantome.
    - Various (Box 207, Folder 103)
      Pinocchio Overture, Five Pieces for Winds and Percussion (Philadelphia Wind Quintet), Phantome, Peter Pan, Op. 67.
    - Three Little Dances, Op. 85 (Box 207, Folder 104)
    - Jephta (Symphony No. 5), Op. 89 (Box 207, Folder 105)
    - Jephta (Symphony No. 5), Op. 89 (Box 207, Folder 106)
    - Jephta (Symphony No. 5), Op. 89 (Box 207, Folder 107)
    - Symphony No. 5, Op. 89, Mar 13, 1964 (Box 207, Folder 108)
      Boston Symphony Orchesta, Lewisdorf, cond. (Premiere broadcast.)
    - Symphony No. 5, Op. 89, Mar 13, 1964 (Box 207, Folder 109)
      Boston Symphony, Lewisdorf, cond.
    - Three Pantomimes, Op. 91, 92, 94, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 110)
    - Three Pantomimes, Op. 91, 92, 94, 1972 (Box 208, Folder 111)
    - Symphony No. 6, Op. 93 (Box 208, Folder 112)
      Radio-Orchester Beromünster, Erich Schmid, cond.
    - Symphony No. 6, Op. 93, Oct 30, 1967 (Box 208, Folder 113)
    - Symphony No. 6, Op. 93; Bunte (Motley) Suite, Op. 48 (Box 208, Folder 114)
    - Seventh Symphony, Op. 95 (Box 208, Folder 115)
      (Munich)
    - Seventh Symphony, Op. 95 (Box 208, Folder 116)
      Munich Philharmonic, Rudolph Albert, cond.
    - Sinfonietta für Streichorchester, Op. 96 (Box 208, Folder 117)
    - Sinfonietta for Strings, Op. 96 (Box 208, Folder 118)
    - Sinfonietta for Wind Instruments and Percussion, Op. 97 (Box 208, Folder 119)
    - Quartet for oboe, clarinet, bassoon, and viola, Op. 98 (Box 208, Folder 120)
      Performance at Library of Congress.
    - Circus Ouverture, 1968 (Box 208, Folder 121)
    - Circus Ouverture, 1968 (Box 208, Folder 122)
      Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra of New York, Andre Kostelanetz, cond.
    - Circus Ouverture (Box 208, Folder 123)
    - Circus Overture (Box 208, Folder 124)
    - Dedication, 1948 (Box 208, Folder 125)
    - Dedication, 1948 (Box 208, Folder 126)
    - Various (Box 208, Folder 127)
      Dedication, 1948; 2nd Symphony; 4th Symphony.
    - "The Covenant" from The Genesis Suite (1945), 1973 (Box 208, Folder 128)
      Werner Jennsef, cond.
    - "The Covenant" from The Genesis Suite (1945) (Box 208, Folder 129)
    - Valse; Fuge aus der Geographie (Box 208, Folder 130)
    - Geographical Fugue, 1963 (Box 208, Folder 131)
      (Decca DL 10073)
    - Valse; Fuge aus der Geographie (Box 208, Folder 132)
    - Geographic Fugue (Box 208, Folder 133)
    - Ladies in Retirement (Box 208, Folder 134)
      Columbia Pictures Orchestra. Morris Stolof, cond.
    - Ladies in Retirement (Box 208, Folder 135)
    - Pinocchio Overture (Box 208, Folder 136)
      Philharmonia Orchestra of Hamburg, Hans-Jurgen Walther, cond.
    - Pinocchio Overture (Box 208, Folder 137)
      Chicago Symphony Orchestra, Stockowski, cond.
    - "Intermezzo," "Epilogue" (Box 208, Folder 138)
    - Toch Festival Memorial Concert - UCLA (tape 1), 1974 November 22; open reel audio tape (Box 208, Folder 139)
    - Toch Festival Memorial Concert - UCLA (tape 2), 1974 November 22; open reel audio tape (Box 208, Folder 140)
    - Ernst Toch Commemorative - UCLA, Nov 22, 1974 (Box 208, Folder 141)
      Tape 1
    - Ernst Toch Commemorative - UCLA, Nov 22, 1974 (Box 208, Folder 142)
      Tape 2
    - Dedication concert for the Ernst Toch Archive, Dec 11, 1967 (Box 208, Folder 143)
      UCLA Chamber Orchestra, Mehli Mehta, cond. Includes Kammersymphonie, Tanz-Suite, Op. 30.
    - "Toch Music I" (Box 208, Folder 144)
    - "Toch Music II" (Box 208, Folder 145)
    - "Toch Music III" (Box 208, Folder 146)
    - Aurelio De La Vega: Symphony in Four Parts, Trio for Flute, Oboe and Clarinet. (Box 208, Folder 147)
      Given to Toch.
    - Vladimir Ussachevsky: "A Piece for Tape Recorder." (Box 208, Folder 148)
    - Selections, 1967 December; open reel audio tape (Box 209, Folder 149)
      Broadcast Rias, Peter Jona Korn. Includes: Pinocchio Overture -- 5 Pieces for Winds and Percussion -- Phantoms -- Peter Pan.
    - Miniature Overture, open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 219)
    - Symphony No.2. op.73, 1970 July 15; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 220)
    - Symphony No. 6,op.93, 1968 January 20; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 221)
    - Sinfonietta fur Streichorchester,op.96, 1967 December 7; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 222)
    - Symphony No.2 op.73, 1954 November 12; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 223)
      Live performance.
    - Divertimento, violin and cello, op.37,no.1, 1968 February 9; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 224)
    - Symphony no.4, op.80, undated; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 225)
    - Kammersymphonie.(1906) Tanz-Suite, op.30 (1924)., 1967 December 11; open reel audio tape (Box 210, Folder 226)
    - [Title Unknown], open reel audio tape (Box 211)
      Publisher no.: C6002
    - Bunte Suite fur Orchester, Op. 48, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Cello Concerto, Op. 35, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Divertimento, Op. 37, no. 1., open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Fuge aus der Geographie. Valse., open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Komoedie fuer Orchester, Op. 42, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Ladies in Retirement, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Piano Concerto, op. 38, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Profiles, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Symphony No. 5, 1965 March 14; open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Symphony No. 7, Op. 95, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - The Princess and the Pea, Op. 43, 1961; open reel audio tape (Box 211)
      Wilmette, IL: Herbert Zipper, director.
    - The Princess and the Pea, Op. 43, 1961; open reel audio tape (Box 211)
    - Third Symphony, open reel audio tape (Box 211)
      Publisher no.: P8364
    - Chamber Music. Selections, 1974 May 13; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 227)
      String Trio op.63 -- Divertimento for Violin & Cello; op.37,no,1.
    - Sonata, violin & piano, op.44, 1963 March 14; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 230)
      Recorded by Radio Zurich. Divertimento, violin & viola,op.37,no.2,bd.2.
    - Big Ben op.62, Burlesken, Ideas, op.69, 1968 December 3; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 231)
    - Gesprochene Musik.Fuge aus der Geographie, 1969 August 21; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 232)
    - Quartet, strings,no.3,op.18, D flat major., 1969 January 24; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 233)
      opus 3, 1: Quasi prolog.Langsam
      2: Lebhaft
      3:Andante
      4:allegro giocoso,br. opus 18, 1: Allegro impetuoso ed appassionato
      Serenade (Spitweg) in g, op.25 (1917)
    - Divertimento,violin & viola, op.37,no.2., undated; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 234)
    - Quartets, strings, no.7,op.70. Trio, strings ,op.63, 1969 February 14; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 235)
      0p.70, 1:Calmly and evenly flowing, with tenderness
      2: Adagio
      3: Pensive Serenade
      4: Vigorous
      op.63, 1: Allegro
      3: Allegro
    - Selections, undated; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 236)
      Symphony no. 5 -- Passsacaglia and fugue,orchestra, Morel,Francois -- Antiphone
    - The Chinese Flute, 1970 May 3; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 237)
      6 mvts.
    - Miniature Overture, 1972 October 21; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 238)
    - Kleinstadtbilder, Op. 49; Ideas, Op. 69, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 239)
    - Big Ben, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 240)
    - Egon und Emilie, Op. 46, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 241)
      English version, Pepperdine College.
    - Piano Concerto No. 2, Op. 61, 1970 January 5; open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 242)
    - Streich Quartett, Op. 74, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 243)
    - Klavierkonzert, Op. 61, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 244)
    - Five Pieces for winds and percussion, Op. 83; Sonatinetta, op. 84, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 245)
    - Poems to Martha, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 246)
    - Piano Quintet, Op. 64, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 252)
    - Valse, open reel audio tape (Box 211, Folder 253)
    - Chamer Music :selections, 1973?; open reel audio tape (Box 221)
      Profiles,op.68,bd.1;Sonata for violin and piano,op.2,bds.2-4
    - Quartet for Strings, Op.74, 1954 April 25; open reel audio tape (Box 221)
  - Open reel: Lectures/other, Subseries 3.
    - "Evenings on the Roof." Parts 1, 2 & 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Peter Yates and Gerald Strang on Toch.
    - "Ernst Toch Speaks.", 1967 (Box 209, Folder 183)
      Address by Toch in German, English translation read by Sam Jaffe. Also introduction to 3rd Symphony, 1955.
    - English Translation of RIAS speech Berlin (Box 209, Folder 184)